

## CONTACT

+94772934671

maneesh.15@cse.mrt.ac.lk

No: 43/77, Isuru Pedesa, Mampitiya, Galle

# SOCIAL

in linkedin.com/in/maneeshaindrachapa

github.com/maneeshaindrachapa

maneeshaindrachapa.github.io

medium.com/@maneeshaindrachapa

stackoverflow.com/users/16497617/ma neesha-indrachapa

# MANEESHA INDRACHAPA

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To continuously enhance my knowledge, skills and experiences by getting involved in a challenging environment in the field of Computer Science and Engineering while committing towards personal and organizational growth to the best of my ability.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer**

# WSO2 (Pvt) Ltd | Nov 2020 - Present

Worked with the Identity and Access Management team improving and extending capabilities of the Identity Server, Added new functionalities to the identity server. such as SMS and Email OTP authorization. Main technologies used JAVA/J2EE. OSGi, Maven, Git, OpenAPI, OAuth, Microservices, LDAP

# Software Engineer

## Codegen International (Pvt) Ltd | Feb 2020 - Oct 2020

Was assigned to an ongoing project which uses Java, Angular4, OracleDB and several other technologies. Had the opportunity to develop the caching system on the project which handles every transaction.

# Trainee Software Engineer

#### Arimac Lanka (Pvt) Ltd | Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

Was assigned to a Game Development facility at Arimac and had an opportunity to contribute to the Nero video game by developing several game functionalities including performance enhancement.

#### **PROJECTS**

# An Intelligent Sinhala - English Dictionary / Thesaurus / Word Look-Up Tool

This was the Undergraduate final year research project. In this project, a Thesaurus, Dictionary and Word-Look-Up tool for Sinhala - English Languages was created using word embeddings and distance measurement algorithms.

## **REST API support for SMS and Email OTPs**

This project exposes SMS and Email OTP generation and validation as fully decoupled Java OSGI services for the WSO2 Platform. These REST APIs can be easily integrated into any enterprise solution. Furthermore, they were created to effectively addressed many security scenarios such as DDoS attacks, Brute force, Performance degradation, etc.

### WeAtWe - Social Media Web site

This is an ongoing project which is a social media website for philanthropists, where they can promote their good causes, donations, and also organize charity events.

# Vortex - Organizational Voting Ballot Management System

This is a voting ballot system designed for organizational decision making using a voting ballot. This facilitates an unbiased and efficient way for employees to participate in organizational decision making. In this application, managers can create a voting poll and add the employees to vote in the voting poll.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **Programming Languages**

- Java
- Python
- C#

#### Web Development

- HTML
- CSS
- Angular
- JavaScript
- PHP
- NodeJS

## **Mobile Development**

- Ionic 3
- Android

#### **Database**

- MySQL
- SOL Server
- MongoDB
- OracleDB

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS**

- Placed within top 200 teams out of 7200 competition teams in DengAl competition held by Driven Data
- Placed among top 10 teams in MoraXtreme
  2 0
- IT Director of Best IT-enabled Leo Club in Sri Lanka 2017/2018
- Won several inter-school and all-island Chess tournaments.
- School and District Color holder for Chess
- Southern Province 3rd Place in School Do-You-Know competition in 2007
- Primary and Junior Prefect in Richmond College, Galle

#### **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

#### **Director of IT**

- Leo Club of University of Moratuwa MAY 2017 - AUG 2018
- Developed Official UoM LEOs web page

#### Exmo & Night of the Brethren

- Developed Exmo Treasure hunt Web page
- Developed Count Down and Treasure Hunt Web Page for Night of the Brethren

# Backpacker

This is an app that helps travellers to find travelling locations with predicted weather conditions and location details such as humidity, temperature, etc.

# AccomodateME -Online Boarding Auctioning System

AccomodateME is an online boarding house searching application which has been designed to help students of University of Moratuwa in finding a suitable accommodating environment.

# **Carbon - Shopping Complex Managing App**

Carbon is a mobile application made for a shopping complex to manage its shops and customers. Using this, customers can order the items they want from multiple shops without walking in to shops.

#### CleanSI

CleanSL is a mobile application that was developed to track the location of garbage collecting vehicles and give notifications to the users when the garbage collecting truck is en route. This project was done in collaboration with Ingenii-Lanka Pvt Ltd.

#### Plutonium

Plutonium is a simple virus analyser made using Java. It uses a MD5 hash registry from VirusShare. It is capable of generating a report stating whether a given file is infected or not. If infected then the type of virus is identified. This is done using an API service supplied by VirusTotal.

# **Bulk User Migration On WS02 Identity Server**

This project was done as an Open source contribution for the WSO2 Identity Server. Previously, even though the WSO2 identity server was capable of Bulk User migration through the web interface. there was a certain performance issue if the user count was high, to mitigate this issue an OSGi service was developed which can handle millions of user migrations within milliseconds.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Robert Gordon University, UK

MSc in Big Data Analytics | 2020 - Present CGPA - 3.70

# University of Moratuwa - Department of Computer Science and Engineering

B.Sc Engineering Hons | 2015 - 2020

# Charted Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA)

Sep 2014 - Dec 2015

CIMA Diploma in Management Accounting

## Richmond College, Galle

G.C.E. Advanced Level Examination in Physical Stream | 2014

2A Passes and B Pass

G.C.E. Ordinary Level Examination | 2011 8A Passes and B Pass for English Literature

## REFERENCES

# Eng, Prof. Gihan Dias

PhD (UCD), MSc (UCSB), BSc Eng. (Hons) (Moratuwa), MIE (SL), CEng

email - gihan@uom.lk tel - +94777761626

# Mr. Sugeesh Chandraweera

Senior Software Engineer at Arimac Lanka (PVT) Ltd email - sugeesh@arimaclanka.com tel - +94710416336